wholenewmom.com 2019-03-07

# Privacy Policy - Whole New Mom

Whole New Mom found at https://wholenewmom.com/ (“Website”) is governed by the following privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”)….

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website.

### What Information Do We Collect And How Is It Used?

**Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website** : We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.

**Automatically-Collected Information** : We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

**Cookies** : We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

### How Your Information May Be Used

**We may use the information collected in the following ways:**

• To operate and maintain the Website;

• To send you newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;

• To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;

• To send you eBooks you have purchased or obtained for free

• To respond to your comments or inquiries;;

• To track and measure advertising on the Website;

• To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

### **Third-Party Use Of Personal Information**

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

**Personal data is collected by Website for the following purposes and using the following third-party service providers:**

**_Analytics_**

Analytics collected directly and Google Analytics

Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

Commercial affiliation

**_Amazon Affiliation and ShareAsale_**

Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

_**Contacting the User**_

Contact form

Personal Data: email address and first name

_**Ecommerce**_

WordPress

Personal Data: email address, first and last name, item purchased, date purchased, total payment amount

_**Interaction with external social networks and platforms**_

Google+ +1 button and social widgets, Facebook Like button and social widgets, Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets and Twitter Tweet button and social widgets

Personal Data: Cookies and Usage Data

_**Managing contacts and sending messages**_

ConvertKit

Personal Data: email address and first name (optional)

_**RSS feed management**_

ConvertKit

Personal Data: Usage Data

_**SPAM protection**_

Akismet

Personal Data: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

_**Traffic optimization and distribution**_

CloudFlare

Personal Data: Cookies and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service

At this time, your personal information is not shared with any other third-party applications. This list may be amended from time to time in the Website’s sole discretion.

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent.

### Anonymous Data

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

### Publicly Visible Information

If you leave a comment on this Website, your name and email may be publicly visible.

### Cookies

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the Website.

### Advertising

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please see: <https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

**Display Ads**

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

**Retargeting Ads**

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone's past visits to the Website.

### Affiliate Program Participation

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Whole New Mom, LLC is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com. As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

### Newsletters

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

### Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

### Rights Related To Your Personal Information

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to be removed from our mailing list.

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Amend – You may contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law such as in the case of eBook sales.

### Sensitive Personal Information

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

### Children's Information

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

### Contact Information

At any time, please contact us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) for questions related to this Privacy Policy.
